Guide to the Hermann Broch Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings of Others, 1901-89; Series III; 1; (2 boxes)
  - GENERAL
    - Federn, Paul
      - "Zur Reform des ärztlichen Spitaldienstes": offprint, 1901 (Box 60, Folder 1493)
    - Federn, Paul and Weiss, Edoardo, "Über einige Fortschritte der psychoanalytischen Forschung": offprint (Box 60, Folder 1494)
    - Henel, Heinrich, "Curt von Faber Du Faur: In Memoriam": printed version, 1966 May (Box 60, Folder 1495)
    - Hib, K. L., "Ueber die Möglichkeit des modernen Portraits": draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1496)
    - Hiller, Kurt (ed.), After Nazism -- Democracy?: printed version, 1945 (Box 60, Folder 1497)
    - Johnson, Alvin Saunders, "Cleopatra and the Roman Chamber of Commerce": printed version (Box 60, Folder 1498)
    - Käfer, Johannes, "James Joyce und das Bewusstsein: Studie über den Ithaka-Mythos": typescript, carbon (Box 60, Folder 1499-1500)
    - Kahler, Alice Loewy ("Lili"), unidentified essay: draft, typescript, photocopy, 1976 (Box 60, Folder 1501)
    - [Kahler, Erich ?], "Entscheidungs- losigkeit und Seinsverlassenheit": draft, typescript, corrected (Box 60, Folder 1502)
    - Kerenyi, Karoly, "Prometheus and Niobe": draft, typescript, carbon, 1947 (Box 60, Folder 1503)
    - Lehner, Frederick, "Jules Supervielle": offprint, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1504)
    - MacIver, R. M., "Der Eine und die Einheit": typescript, carbon (Box 60, Folder 1505)
    - "Parallen zwischen Einzelheiten unserer Phantasie und indischen Anschauungen": draft, typescript, carbons (Box 60, Folder 1506)
    - Pauli, W., "Der Kampf der Geschlechter": draft, typescript, carbon, 1942 May (Box 60, Folder 1507)
    - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, "Duets at the MacDowell Colony," Wort in der Zeit: printed version (with German translation by Hermann Broch), 1956 Jan (Box 60, Folder 1508)
    - Westenrieder, Gottfried, "Der steinerne Gast": draft, typescript and carbon (Box 60, Folder 1509)
- Personal Papers, 1886-1990; Series IV; 3.5; (8 boxes)
  Series IV, Personal Papers (Boxes 61-68), is organized into two subseries: Hermann Broch and Other. The first subseries is arranged alphabetically by folder title; the second, by individual and thereunder by folder title.
  - HERMANN BROCH
    - Art
      von Ripper, Rudolf: drawing of Hermann Broch
      See: Oversize; Box 74a, folder 1806a
    - Austrian television: Hermann Broch portrait, 1986; YCGLMSS1_0002; 1; 00:15:12; There is a hiss on the audio (Box 61, Item barcode 39002102369999)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Bibliographical information, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1511)
    - Bibliography by Klaus W. Jonas, 1952-53 (Box 61, Folder 1512)
    - Biographical information, 1964-75 (Box 61, Folder 1513)
    - Biographical sketch, 1953 (Box 61, Folder 1514-17)
    - Biography by H. F. Broch de Rothermann (French), 1987 Mar (Box 61, Folder 1518)
    - Birth announcement, 1886 Nov 1 (Box 61, Folder 1519)
    - Birthday, Articles in celebration of Hermann Broch's 50th, 1936 (Box 61, Folder 1520)
    - Birthday, Articles in celebration of Hermann Broch's 60th, 1946 (Box 61, Folder 1521)
    - Book plate of Hermann Broch, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1522)
    - Broch family residences in Vienna and Teesdorf, Floor plans of (Box 61, Folder 1523)
    - Broch seen by himself, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1524)
    - Bülow family miscellany, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1525)
    - Calling cards, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1526)
    - Clippings, 1936-46, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1527)
      See also: Oversize, Box 74, folder 1804
    - Correspondence record, 1945-48 (Box 61, Folder 1528)
    - Curriculum vitae, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1529)
    - Death mask of Hermann Broch: Subscription Fund
      See also: Photographs, Box 70, folder 1755; Oversize, Box 74, folder 1805
      - Address list and form letters, 1952 (Box 62, Folder 1530)
      - Financial records, 1952 (Box 62, Folder 1531)
      - Correspondence with Peter Lipman-Wulf, sculptor, 1952 (Box 62, Folder 1532)
      - Correspondence, General
        Most of this correspondence is to or from Jean Starr Untermeyer, principal organizer of the project.
        - Amann, Paul, 1952 Mar 20 (Box 62, Folder 1533)
        - Bergman, Robert, 1952 Apr 6 (Box 62, Folder 1534)
        - Beller, Elmer A. and Margaret, 1952 Mar 14 (Box 62, Folder 1535)
        - Blücher, Heinrich and Hannah (Box 62, Folder 1536)
        - Bollingen Foundation, Inc., 1952 Mar 1 (Box 62, Folder 1537)
        - Borgese, Elisabeth Mann, 1952 Apr 13 (Box 62, Folder 1538)
        - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1952 Mar 12 (Box 62, Folder 1539)
        - Buck, George C., 1952 Mar 21 (Box 62, Folder 1540)
        - Bunzel, Joseph H., 1952 Mar 26 (Box 62, Folder 1541)
        - Butler, Charles E., 1952 Mar 31 (Box 62, Folder 1542)
        - Canby, Marion Posonby Gause, 1952 Feb-Mar (Box 62, Folder 1543)
        - Cassirer, Thomas, 1952 Mar 25 (Box 62, Folder 1544)
        - Duschnitz, Rudolf, 1952 Mar 21 (Box 62, Folder 1545)
        - Faber du Faur, Curt von, 1952 Oct 9 (Box 62, Folder 1546)
        - Ferand, Ernest T. and Emmy, 1952 Mar 28 (Box 62, Folder 1547)
        - Glaubach, Susi, 1952 Mar 19 (Box 62, Folder 1548)
        - Greenberg, Clement, 1952 Oct 8 (Box 62, Folder 1549)
        - Hammerschlag, Ernst, 1952 Mar 31 (Box 62, Folder 1550)
        - Heller, Judith, 1952 Mar 12 (Box 62, Folder 1551)
        - Hertz, Richard, 1952 Apr 3 (Box 62, Folder 1552)
        - Hinshaw, Virgil, 1952 Mar 18 (Box 62, Folder 1553)
        - Holborn, Annemarie, 1952 Mar 15 (Box 62, Folder 1554)
        - Howland, Anna, 1952 Mar 21 (Box 62, Folder 1555)
        - Johnson, Alvin Saunders, 1952 Mar 12 (Box 62, Folder 1556)
        - Judd, Jadwiga, 1952 Apr 12 (Box 62, Folder 1557)
        - Kahler, Erich, 1952 Mar-Oct (Box 62, Folder 1558)
        - Kann, Robert A., 1952 Mar 19 (Box 62, Folder 1559)
        - Lederer, Gertrude, 1952 Mar 12 (Box 62, Folder 1560)
        - Lehner, Frederick, 1952 Mar 30 (Box 62, Folder 1561)
        - Levy, Edith Jonas, 1952 Mar 21 (Box 62, Folder 1562)
        - Loewenthal, Minnie L., 1952 Mar (Box 62, Folder 1563)
        - Lowe, Adolph, 1952 Mar 28 (Box 62, Folder 1564)
        - Lowe, Helen Tracy Porter, 1952 Mar 16 (Box 62, Folder 1565)
        - Mann, Katia, 1952 Mar 25 (Box 62, Folder 1566)
        - Meeske, Regula, 1952 Mar-Apr (Box 62, Folder 1567)
        - Meisel, Marianne, 1952 Apr-May (Box 62, Folder 1568)
        - Mumford, Mr. and Mrs. Lewis, [1952] (Box 62, Folder 1569)
        - Nettl, Paul, 1952 Mar (Box 62, Folder 1570)
        - Oppenheim-Errera, Mr. and Mrs. Paul, 1952 Mar 17 (Box 62, Folder 1571)
        - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1952 Mar 22 (Box 62, Folder 1572)
        - Polzer, Victor, 1952 Mar 28 (Box 62, Folder 1573)
        - Rogers, Frances Colby, 1952 Mar 19 (Box 62, Folder 1574)
        - Rosé, Alfred, 1952 Mar 28 (Box 62, Folder 1575)
        - Rothstein, Irma, 1952 Mar 12 (Box 62, Folder 1576)
        - Sahl, Hans, 1952 Apr (Box 62, Folder 1577)
        - Schabert, Beatrice, 1952 Mar 24 (Box 62, Folder 1578)
        - Schreiber, Carl F., 1952 Feb-Oct (Box 62, Folder 1579)
        - Shahn, Ben, 1952 Mar 18 (Box 62, Folder 1580)
        - Staudinger, Hans and Else, 1952 Mar 17 (Box 62, Folder 1581)
        - Steiner, Herbert, [1952] (Box 62, Folder 1582)
        - Stern, James, 1952 Mar 20 (Box 62, Folder 1583)
        - Urzidil, Johannes, 1952 Mar 14 (Box 62, Folder 1584)
        - Waldinger, Ernst, 1952 Mar 31 (Box 62, Folder 1585)
        - Weigand, Hermann J., 1952 Feb-Oct (Box 62, Folder 1586)
        - Wilmot, Rena A., 1952 Mar 13 (Box 62, Folder 1587)
        - Wing, Donald G., 1952 Mar 10 (Box 62, Folder 1588)
        - Wolff, Eleanor, 1952 Apr 7 (Box 62, Folder 1589)
        - Wolff, Kurt H., 1952 Mar 21 (Box 62, Folder 1590)
        - Wyatt, Gertrud L., 1952 Apr 6 (Box 62, Folder 1591)
        - Zimmer, Christiane, 1952 Mar 16 (Box 62, Folder 1592)
        - Unidentified, 1952 Mar 13 (Box 62, Folder 1593)
    - Diary, 1934-35 (Box 62, Folder 1594)
    - Emigration papers, 1938 (Box 62, Folder 1595)
    - Engagement announcement, 1909 Oct (Box 62, Folder 1596)
    - Erkennungskarte, 1936 Mar 23 (Box 62, Folder 1597)
    - Expense account books, 1922-35 (Box 62, Folder 1598-1600)
    - Financial records
      - Bank correspondence, 1949 (Box 62, Folder 1601)
      - Bank statements with canceled checks, 1949-51 (Box 63, Folder 1602)
      - Savings account passbook, 1947-49 (Box 64, Folder 1603)
    - Fund for the Publication and Promotion of Valuable Scientific Works, Proposal for the establishment of (Box 64, Folder 1604)
    - Handwriting analysis by Victor Frank (Box 64, Folder 1605)
    - Hermann Broch-Gasse (Vienna, Austria), Dedication of, 1970 (Box 64, Folder 1606)
    - Hospitalizations in Princeton Hospital (Princeton, New Jersey), 1969 Dec 16 (Box 64, Folder 1607)
    - Human rights information, 1945-48, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1608-09)
    - Inscriptions to and from Hermann Broch (photocopies from books), 1944-50, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1610)
    - Library of Hermann Broch
      - Inventory, copy 1, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1611)
      - Inventory, copy 2, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1612)
      - Supplementary inventory, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1613)
      - Correspondence concerning the sale, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1614-15)
    - Military service documents, 1905-18 (Box 64, Folder 1616)
    - Nobel Prize for Literature: Recommendations
      Most of this correspondence is to or from Alvin Saunders Johnson, principal organizer of the project.
      - Austrian PEN Club, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1617)
      - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1950-51 (Box 64, Folder 1618)
      - Deutsche Akademie für Sprache und Dichtung, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1619)
      - Einstein, Albert, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1620)
      - Eliot, T. S., 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1621)
      - Faulkner, William, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1622)
      - Frank, James, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1623)
      - Fritz-Vietta, Egon, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1624)
      - Gauss, Christian Frederick, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1625)
      - Hesse, Hermann, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1626)
      - Kahler, Erich, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1627)
      - Lange, Victor, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1628)
      - Lehner, Frederick, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1629)
      - Löwi, Otto, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1630)
      - MacLeish, Archibald, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1631)
      - Mann, Thomas, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1632)
      - Moe, Henry Allen, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1633)
      - Pauli, Wolfgang, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1634)
      - Schreiber, Carl F., 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1635)
      - Wilder, Thornton, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1636)
      - Winter, Hanns von, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1637)
    - Notebooks
      - Philosophy (No. 1), n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1638)
      - Philosophy, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1639)
      - Various (No. 2), n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1640)
      - Poems (No. 4), n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1641)
    - Obituaries, 1951-52 (Box 64, Folder 1642)
    - Obituaries, 1951-52 (Box 65, Folder 1643-45)
    - Patents for cotton textile machinery, 1907
      See: Oversize, Box 74, folder 1806
    - Prison release documents (Bad-Aussee, Austria), 1938 (Box 65, Folder 1646)
    - Report cards, 1893-1906 (Box 65, Folder 1647)
    - Report on my activities in rescuing endangered European writers, 1941 Oct (Box 65, Folder 1648)
    - Stationery, blank sheet, signed, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1649)
    - Student notebooks (titles by Broch)
      - Bernheim, Historische Methode, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1650)
      - Carnap, Axiomatische Geometrie, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1651)
      - Carnap, Philosophie der Arithmatik, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1652)
      - Diverses (mathematical content), n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1653)
      - Furtwängler, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1654)
      - Furtwängler, Algebra, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1655)
      - Furtwängler, Zahlentheorie, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1656)
      - Hahn
        - 1-113, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1657-59)
        - 100-185 (Box 66, Folder 1660)
        - II, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1661)
        - Ergänzungen, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1662)
        - Kurventheorie, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1663)
      - Hahn (cont.)
        - Vortragsübungen II, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1664)
        - Uebungen II, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1665)
      - Logische Hermaneutik, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1666)
      - Menger
        - Menger, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1667-68)
        - Differentialgeometrie, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1669)
        - Elementargeometrie, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1670)
        - Mengentheoretische Geometrie, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1671)
      - Natorp, Logische Grundlagen der exakten Wissenschaften (Teubner 1910) (Box 66, Folder 1672)
      - Philosophische Uebungen, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1673)
      - Vaihinger (No. 5), n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1674)
      - Zahlentheoretische Uebungen, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1675)
      - No title [group theory], n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1676)
      - No title [group theory], n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1677-82)
      - No title [integrals], n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1683)
      - No title [logic content], n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1684)
      - No title [mathematics], n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1685-89)
      - No title [philosophy], n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1690)
    - Teesdorfer Rekonvaleszentenhaus, 1919 Oct 26 (Box 67, Folder 1691)
    - Verwandten von Hermann Broch, Einige Daten über die (Box 67, Folder 1692)
    - War ration book, 1943 (Box 67, Folder 1693)
    - Wedding announcement, 1909 Dec 11 (Box 67, Folder 1694)
    - Wedding dinner menu, 1909 Dec 11 (Box 67, Folder 1695)
    - Wills, 1947-51 (Box 67, Folder 1696)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1937-50, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1697)
  - OTHER
    - Allesch, Ea von: biographical sketch, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1698)
    - Broch, Johanna Sara Schnabel
      - Reichsfluchtsteuer documents, 1940-41 (Box 68, Folder 1699)
      - Silhouette of Johanna with Hermann Broch, 1888 (Box 68, Folder 1700)
    - Broch, Josef
      - Letters by Hermann and Fritz Broch for their father's birthday, 1899 Jan 12 (Box 68, Folder 1701)
      - Poem by Hermann Broch for his father's birthday, 1908 Jan 12 (Box 68, Folder 1702)
      - "Programmbuch" by Hermann and Fritz Broch for their father's birthday, 1899 Jan 12 (Box 68, Folder 1703)
      - Sympathy acknowledgement card, 1933 Oct (Box 68, Folder 1704)
    - Broch, Josef and Johanna
      - Engagement announcements, 1885 Sep (Box 68, Folder 1705)
      - Wedding invitations, 1885 Oct 25 (Box 68, Folder 1706)
    - Broch de Rothermann, Hermann Friedrich
      - Account of his years in France, 1939-41, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1707)
      - Expense account book, 1929-30 (Box 68, Folder 1708)
      - Handwriting analysis, 1950 Aug (Box 68, Folder 1709)
      - Job search, 1948 Mar 1 (Box 68, Folder 1710)
      - Lecture in Stuttgart (cassette tape recording), 1986 Nov 1 (Box 68, Folder 1711)
    - Broch von Rothermann, Franziska
      - Baptismal and marriage certificates of the forebears of FBvR (assembled for the so-called "Ariernachweis"), 1938 (Box 68, Folder 1712)
      - Death announcement, 1975 Jan (Box 68, Folder 1713)
    - Bródy, Dániel: death announcement, 1969 (Box 68, Folder 1714)
    - Canby, Marion Ponsonby Gause: obituary, 1974 (Box 68, Folder 1715)
    - Fleischmann, Trude: biographical sketch and obituary, 1986-90 (Box 68, Folder 1716)
    - Johnson, Alvin Saunders: honorary dinners, 1949, 1959 (Box 68, Folder 1717)
    - Kahler, Alice: conversation about Hermann Broch (cassette tape recording), n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1718)
    - Kahler, Erich: recommendation for Guggenheim fellowship by Hermann Broch, 1941 Dec (Box 68, Folder 1719)
    - Norden, Ruth: biographical information, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1720)
    - Pierrakos, Eva Wassermann Broch: obituary (first wife of H. F. Broch de Rothermann), 1979 (Box 68, Folder 1721)
    - Polzer, Victor
      - Obituary, 1966 Feb (Box 68, Folder 1722)
      - Recommendation by Hermann Broch, 1942 Nov 15 (Box 68, Folder 1723)
    - Untermeyer, Jean Starr
      - Dustjackets of various books, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1724)
      - Interview between JSU and Kenneth Nesheim, chiefly concerning her translation of Der Tod des Virgil (reel to reel tape recording), 1969 May 28 (Box 68, Folder 1725)
    - Weismann, Willi: death announcement, 1983 (Box 68, Folder 1726)
- Photographs, 1872-1986; Series V; 2.5; (4 boxes)
  Series V, Photographs (Boxes 69-72), is organized into two subseries: Hermann Broch and Other. In the first subseries, the materials are arranged into categories and thereunder alphabetically; in the second, alphabetically by surname.
  - HERMANN BROCH
    - Single shots
      - Childhood, 1889-93 (Box 69, Folder 1727)
      - Adolescence and early manhood, 1901-10 (Box 69, Folder 1728)
      - Adulthood, 1930-50 (Box 69, Folder 1729)
        See also: Box 72, folder 1791
    - Group shots
      - Adulthood, c. 1920 (Box 69, Folder 1731)
        See also: Box 72, folder 1792
      - Childhood, 1893-94 (Box 69, Folder 1730)
    - Photographs by Broch, Annemarie Meier-Graefe
      - Broch's hospital stay in Princeton, New Jersey, 1949 (Box 69, Folder 1732-33)
    - Photographs by Fleischmann, Trude
      - Portraits, c. 1948 (Box 69, Folder 1734)
        See also: Box 72, folder 1793
    - Photographs by Geiringer, Trude
      - Album
        See: Box 72, folder 1794
      - Broch in the Geiringer apartment (Vienna, Austria), 1936 Feb (Box 69, Folder 1735)
      - Broch in Gosau (Austria), 1933 May (Box 69, Folder 1736)
      - Broch in Hinterbruehl-Moedling (Austria), 1933 Oct (Box 69, Folder 1737)
      - Broch in the Wienerwald (Austria), 1935 (Box 69, Folder 1738)
      - Broch with the Bródys, 1933-34 (Box 69, Folder 1739)
      - Broch with Frank Thiess, 1936 Dec (Box 69, Folder 1740)
      - Entsühnung premiere (commemorative photograph album), 1934 Mar 15 (Box 69, Folder 1741)
      - Miscellany, 1933-36, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1742-43)
    - Photographs of drawings of Hermann Broch
      - Birchman caricature, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1744)
      - Derso caricature, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1745)
      - Ripper, Rudolf von, drawing (Box 70, Folder 1746)
    - Residences
      - Franz-Josefs-Kai 37, Vienna, Austria (birthplace), n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1747)
      - 1 Evelyn Place, Princeton, New Jersey (Kahler house), 1953-63 (Box 70, Folder 1748)
      - 78 Lake Place, New Haven, Connecticut (last residence), n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1749)
    - Broch memorials: Busts
      - Mahler bust
        See: Photographs by Geiringer, Trude - album, p. 5, Box 72, folder 1794
      - Ferand bust, 1934 (Box 70, Folder 1750)
        See also: Photographs by Geiringer, Trude - album, p. 10, Box 72, folder 1794
      - Peschke bust (Teesdorf, Austria), 1966 (Box 70, Folder 1751)
      - Plunguian bust, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1752)
        See also: Box 72, folder 1795
      - Rothstein bust, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1753)
      - Unna bust, 1986 (Box 70, Folder 1754)
    - Broch memorials: Death masks
      - Lipman-Wulf death mask, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1755)
    - Broch memorials: Monuments
      - Monument (bust on pedestal) in Hermann Broch-Park (Teesdorf, Austria), n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1756)
      - Tombstone in cemetery in Union District of Killingworth, Connecticut, 1952-65, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1757)
    - Broch memorials: Tablets
      - Author's residence (Teesdorf, Austria), 1976 May 30 (Box 70, Folder 1758)
      - Birthplace (Vienna, Austria), n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1759)
      - Site of composition of the novel Der Versucher (Mösern, Austria), 1964-65 (Box 70, Folder 1760)
    - Broch Museum
      - Broch Museum and monument, Dedication of (Teesdorf, Austria): commemorative photograph album, 1967 Feb (Box 70, Folder 1761)
      - Interior views (Teesdorf, Austria), 1974 Nov 10 (Box 70, Folder 1762)
    - Plays
      - Aus der Luft gegriffen (Osnabrück, Germany), 1981 (Box 70, Folder 1763)
      - Die Entsühnung
        See: Photographs of Geiringer, Trude, Box 72, folder 1794
  - OTHER
    - Bülow, Arthur, 1915 (Box 71, Folder 1764)
    - Bülow, Baroness, 1914 (Box 71, Folder 1765)
    - Broch, Annemarie Meier-Graefe, c. 1949 (Box 71, Folder 1766)
    - Broch family, 1892-1910 (Box 71, Folder 1767)
    - Broch, Friedrich Josef ("Fritz"), 1916-30 (Box 71, Folder 1768)
    - Broch, Josef, 1872-1933 (Box 71, Folder 1769)
    - Broch, Johanna, 1880-1930 (Box 71, Folder 1770)
    - Broch, Josef and Johanna, 1885-1932 (Box 71, Folder 1771)
    - Broch, Josef and Johanna: honeymoon trip, 1885 (Box 71, Folder 1772)
    - Broch de Rothermann, Hermann Friedrich, 1944-58 (Box 71, Folder 1773)
    - Broch de Rothermann, Hermann Friedrich and Sachi, 1958 (Box 71, Folder 1774)
    - Johnson, Alvin Saunders (Box 71, Folder 1775)
    - Kahler, Alice Loewy ("Lili"), 1972, 1986 (Box 71, Folder 1776)
    - Kahler, Antoinette ("Mama"), 1942 (Box 71, Folder 1777)
    - Kahler, Erich, 1940-61 (Box 71, Folder 1778)
    - Kahler, Erich and Alice Loewy ("Lili"), 1963 (Box 71, Folder 1779)
    - Rothermann, Franziska von ("Fanny"), 1900-06 (Box 71, Folder 1780)
    - Rothermann, Irene von ("Sophie"), 1899 Jul 11 (Box 71, Folder 1781)
    - Rothermann, Marie von Hann von, 1892 (Box 71, Folder 1782)
    - Rothermann residence (Hirm, Austria), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1783)
    - Rothermann, Rudolf von, 1898 (Box 71, Folder 1784)
    - Schnabel, Flora Engelmann, 1916 (Box 71, Folder 1785)
    - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1934-40, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1786)
    - Werfel, Franz, 1943 (Box 71, Folder 1786a)
      Photograph by Trude Geiringer
    - Wessely, Fred, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1787)
    - Windisch-Graetz, Stephanie and Rudi von (Box 71, Folder 1788)
    - Wolf, Felix, ca. 1915 (Box 71, Folder 1789)
    - Miscellany, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1790)
  - HERMANN BROCH: OVERSIZE
    - Single shoots: adulthood, 1943, n.d. (Box 72 (Oversize), Folder 1791)
    - Group shots: adulthood (Yaddo), 1939 (Box 72 (Oversize), Folder 1792)
    - Photographs by Fleischmann, Trude, 1947 (Box 72 (Oversize), Folder 1793)
    - Photographs by Geiringer, Trude - album, 1933-36 (Box 72 (Oversize), Folder 1794)
    - Broch memorials: busts - Plunguian bust, n.d. (Box 72 (Oversize), Folder 1795)
- Addition, 1925-1990s; Series VI; 3.83
  Series VI, Addition (Boxes 75-80), is organized into five subseries: Correspondence, Writings, Writings of Others, Personal Papers, and Photographs. Within each series, materials are arranged alphabetically by name or subject.
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence of Hermann Broch
      - Blei, Franz (Box 75)
      - Broch, Annemarie Meier-Graefe (Box 75)
      - Bródy, Dániel (Box 75)
      - Bryan, Katherine McKenty (Box 75)
      - Federn, Paul (Box 75)
      - Hoffer, Hedwig (Box 75)
      - Judd, Jadwiga (Box 75)
      - Kahler, Alice Loewy (Box 75)
      - Kahler, Erich (Box 75)
      - Koller, Dr. (Box 75)
      - Loewy, Hanna (Box 75)
      - Silver, Ruth (Box 75)
      - Suhrkamp Verlag (Box 75)
      - Untermeyer, Jean Starr (Box 75)
      - Unidentified (Box 75)
    - Correspondence of Kahler family
      - Unidentified (Box 75)
  - Writings
    - Aus der Luft gegriffen oder Die Geschäfte des Baron Laborde, English translation by Dennis Porter (Box 75)
    - "Bemerkungen zur Utopie einer 'International Bill of Rights and of Responsibilities'." "Bill of Rights -- Bill of Duties: Utopia and Reality," typescript, mimeograph (Box 75)
    - Entwurf für Massenpsychologie I. "A Study of Mass Hysteria," typescript mimeograph (Box 75)
    - Die Erzählung der Magd Zerline, French-language production with Jeanne Moreau, YCGLMSS1_0001; 1; 02:08:38; There is a hiss on the audio. (Box 75, Item barcode 39002102339455)
    - Die Erzählung der Magd Zerline, posters
      See: Oversize, Box 79 Roll
    - Hofmannsthal und seine Zeit, typescript carbon (Box 76)
    - Poems, autograph manuscript (Box 76)